

♀ 2nd lane, sarada park nabanagar, 700051 kolkata, India 🔀 biswajitisgpp7890@gmail.com 📞 9836126750

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/biswajit-roy-682126215/ □ 05/05/1989 UnMarried □ Indian in https://www.linkedin.com/in/biswajit-roy-682126215/

Attps://stackoverflow.com/users/16254447/biswajit-roy k https://www.kaggle.com/biswajitroy7890/code

https://www.fiverr.com/biswajitroy983?public\_mode=true

## **Profile**

A Data Science Enthusiast having experience over all of 9 years in Automation Industry and now currently working as an Mentor in world Bank funded project in West Bengal Panchayat & Rural Development .Learnt Data Science and Deep Learning and also Active participator of Analytics Vidhya, MachineHack , Driven Data and Kaggle

## **Data Science Competition Summary**

MachineHack:- Rank 254 Link:-https://machinehack.com/user/userinfo/ui ☑

Analytics Vidhya: - Rank 575 Link:-https://datahack.analyticsvidhya.com/user/

DrivenData:-Link:-https://www.drivendata.org/users/BiswajitRoy/ ☑

Some Best Submissions are America's Next Top (Statistical) Model - 2020, Flu Shot Learning: Predict H1N1 and Seasonal Flu Vaccines, DengAI: Predicting Disease Spread

Kaggle:- unranked Link:-https://www.kaggle.com/biswajitroy7890 ☑

Some Best Submissions are Natural Language Processing with Disaster Tweets, Digit Recognizer, Tabular Playground Series - Jan 2021

# **Internships**

Machine Learning with IOT Sensor, iNeuron.ai 05/2021 – present

Retriving data from Envirionmental sensors & Agricultural sensors and perform Algorithms to provide Time Series Prediction with MLOPS integration

**Fake News Detection,** *Ivy Professional School* 03/2021 – 04/2021

Text Mining & Machine Learning

Classification Problem on Predicting Employee's Promotion Using Python, 12/2020 – 01/2021

Ivy Professional School

# **Certificates**

**Data Science & Analytics** 

Ivy Professional School

**Intro To SQL** 

Kaggle

Certificate program in Public Procurement(MOOC) by The World Bank Group

Coursera

Certificate in Deep Learning, Adv NLP & Computer Vision

iNeuron.ai

Adv SQL Kaggle

Certificate program in contract management (MOOC) by The World Bank Group

Coursera

## Skills

| python                       | $\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\bullet$ | Machine Learning             | • • • • • |
|------------------------------|---|------------------------------|-----------|
| Deep learning                | $\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\bullet$ | Tensorflow 2.0               | • • • • • |
| Keras                        | • • • • •                               | Object Detection             | • • • • • |
| AI & ML Cloud deploymet      | • • • • •                               | PYTORCH                      | • • • • • |
| ADV NLP & NLP                | • • • • •                               | Spark MLlib                  | • • • • • |
| Mxnet                        | • • • • •                               | AutoML,H2O,FASTAI            | • • • • • |
| Docker,GCP Kubernates,MLFLOW | • • • • •                               | AWS SageMaker,Comprehend,Lex | • • • • • |
| Github                       | • • • • •                               | MLOPS GCP ,AWS               | • • • • • |

## **Professional Experience**

# ISGPP-II, PANCHAYAT & RURAL DEVELOPMENT, WEST BENGAL, IT MENTOR Montoring support for the strengthening the local self-government in the strengthening the strengthening

Mentoring support for the strengthening the local self government in terms Management, procurement, Policy making, Administration, Resource Mobilization and Information technology. Provide support and mentoring to the panchayat officials on GPMS (online Accounting system).

04/2017 – present kolkata, India

### Honeywell Automation india Limited, System Operator

Monitoring and Supervising Access control System, CCTV Survelliance, Fire Alarm System and other Honeywell based products. Email Handling. Proficient in MS Word, MS Excel, SQL, Ms powerpoint, Preparation / Maintenance of weekly and monthly Metrics / Error tracking.

10/2011 – 06/2016 kolkata, India

### **Education**

**Bachelor in computer Application,** Netaji Shubhas open University

07/2007 – 12/2010 kolkata, India

### **Interests**

Actively participates in Hackathons, Attends Data Science Seminars & Kaggle Days Meetup, Watch Movie Clips

# **Awards**

https://www.facebook.com/ivyproschool/photos/10159104578676812, ivy Professional School

## **Some Youtube Publication**

How i Secured 16th Rank in MachineHack Competition .https://youtu.be/Q\_ihgYRHmWo ☑

Twitter Sentiment Analysis | Natural Language Processing | Python | US Elections 2020 | Biswajit Roy https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-D2AaOXMCuc&list=PL6ajVQ6jyjvBNzNS9GBB1QfiNzRJ--F1t&index=17 ☑